A Guide to the John C. Bugher papers FA027
Rockefeller Archive Center
John C. Bugher papers
1926-1966
Rockefeller Archive Center
Loutit, John F.
Warren, Shields
Taylor, L. S.
Strauss, Lewis L.
Taylor, Grant
Cheng, Ping-Yao
Kumm, Henry W. (Henry William)
Muench, Hugo
Putnam, Persis
Kerr, J. Austin, 1900-
Cannan, R. Keith (Robert Keith)
Holmes, Robert
U.S. Atomic Energy Commission
U.S. Atomic Energy Commission. Division of Biology and Medicine
Bugher, John C.
FA027
22.05 Cubic Feet 63 document cases
Arrangement note
The John C. Bugher collection is divided into seven series:
Series 1 - General Files
Series 2 - Articles, Speeches, Manuscripts
Series 3 - General Reprints
Series 4 - Atomic Energy Commission
Series 5 - Atomic Energy Commission Reprints
Series 6 - Memorabilia
Series 7 - Audiovisual materials
Series 1056 - Photographs
Biographical/Historical note
John C. Bugher (1901-1970) was born in Upland, Indiana. He received his B.S. degree from Taylor University in Upland in 1921. From the University of Michigan he received the following degrees: in 1921, an A.B.; in 1929, an M.D.; and in 1931, an M.S. From 1919-1920, Dr. Bugher served as Instructor in Mathematics and Physics at Taylor University; from March 1926-1928, he was Director of Public Health at South Haven, Michigan; and from 1922 until 1937 he was on the faculty of the University of Michigan, first as Assistant in Bacteriology from 1922-1926, then as Senior Instructor in Pathology from 1929-1932, and finally as Assistant Professor of Pathology from 1933 to 1937, when he resigned to join the Rockefeller Foundation.
His first two months with the Foundation, from October to December 1937, Dr. Bugher spent in the Foundation's Yellow Fever Laboratories in New York City, becoming familiar with current yellow fever research and techniques prior to an assignment to Colombia, South America. At the end of December he left for Colombia to participate in the laboratory and field investigations in yellow fever being carried on there. During his last three years in Columbia (1940-1943), he served as Director of the Seccion de Estudios Especiales. From October 1943 until October 1948, Dr. Bugher's headquarters were in Lagos, Nigeria, West Africa, where he established the Yellow Fever Institute and served as its Director. Here research in yellow fever, including jungle yellow fever, was carried on, involving not only laboratory studies, but field operations in the forest and other areas of that part of Africa. Upon Dr. Bugher's return to the United States, he was again assigned to the Foundation's laboratories, where his particular responsibilities were the biophysical studies of viruses from January 1949 until March 1951.
He was then granted a leave of absence by the Foundation to become Deputy Director of the Division of Biology and Medicine of the U.S. Atomic Energy Commission from 1951-1952, and then Director from 1952 until 1955. In April 1955, Dr. Bugher returned to active duty with the Rockefeller Foundation and was Director for Medical Education and Public Health from then until April 1959, when he was appointed Consultant on Nuclear Energy Affairs. From April to the end of September 1955, the effective date of Dr. Bugher's resignation from the Atomic Energy Commission, he carried dual Foundation and AEC responsibilities.
While with the Atomic Energy Commission, Dr. Bugher participated in the testing of various fission and thermonuclear devices, leading to improved weapons; and was in close touch with research activities in the biological sciences and closely associated with and responsible for many of the developments connected with the peaceful uses of atomic energy in the medical field. In the summer of 1955, Dr. Bugher went to Geneva, Switzerland, as an official adviser to the United States Delegation to the First International Conference on the Peaceful Uses of Atomic Energy. He also attended the Second International Conference in Geneva, in September 1958.
Dr. Bugher was a member of various committees in the field of atomic energy, including the U.S. Atomic Energy Commission's Advisory Committee for Biology and Medicine, of which he was appointed Vice Chairman in January 1959 and Chairman in June 1960; the Committee on Atomic Bomb Casualties and the Committee on Pathological Effects of Atomic Radiation of the National Academy of Sciences-National Research Council; the National Committee on Radiation Protection and Measurements; the By-Laws and Rules Committee and the Nominating Committee of American Nuclear Society, of which he was also a member of the Board of Directors; the American Public Health Association Program Area Committee on Radiological Health; Brookhaven National Laboratory (Associated Universities, Inc.) Medical Department Visiting Committee - elected Chairman in May,1960; Committee on New Frontiers of Technology of the U.S. Chamber of Commerce; Health Physics Advisory Board; Mayor's (New York City) Technical Advisory Committee on Radiation, of which he was Chairman; New York State's General Advisory Committee on Atomic Energy; University of Michigan Law School Atomic Energy Advisory Committee; the World Health Organization Panel on Radiation, and the Puerto Rico Nuclear Center Medical Advisory Committee.
Dr. Bugher was also a member of the National Institute for Disaster Mobilization, Inc., and the New York City Health Research Advisory Council.
His membership in scientific societies included the Academy of Political Science; Federation of American Societies for Experimental Pathology and Experimental Biology; American Association of Pathologists and Bacteriologists; the Michigan Pathological Society; the American Cancer Society; the American Association of Cancer Research; the American Medical Association; the American Society of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene; the Royal Society of Tropical Medicine; the Royal Geographical Society; the American Public Health Association; the Health Physics Society; the American Nuclear Society; the Radiation Research Society; the New York Academy of Sciences, the honorary societies of Alpha Omega Alpha and Sigma Xi. At the University of Michigan, he was a member of the Gamma Alpha Sigma and Phi Rho Sigma fraternities.
During Dr. Bugher's services with the Foundation and the U.S. Atomic Energy Commission, he received various honors, including the award from the President of Colombia in 1943 of the Cruz de Boyaca, and life and honorary membership in the Academy of Medicine of Bogota, Colombia; the bestowal on him in 1948 of the Commander of the Order of the British Empire; the honorary degree of Sc.D. from Taylor University in 1953; the presentation on September 20, 1955, by Chairman Lewis Strauss of the U.S. Atomic Energy Commission's Distinguished Service Award and Superior Accomplishment Award; the receipt on May 9, 1956, of the Howard Taylor Ricketts' Award at the University of Chicago, and the Alumnus of the Y ear Award for 1956, from Taylor University on June 1, 1956. In December 1958, Dr. Bugher was made an Honorary Member of the Faculty of Medicine of the University of Chile in Santiago. He was unanimously elected a Fellow of The New York Academy of Sciences on December 3, 1959, in "outstanding recognition for scientific achievement and promotion of Science."
Scope and Contents note
Important subjects covered in this collection include: fallout, atomic medicine, disaster mobilization, civil defense, genetics, Japan, radiobiology, information retrieval, yellow fever, cancer, radiation, Congressional hearings, hunting and fishing, pathology, leukemia, and malaria.
Among the correspondents are: Persis Putnam, J. A. Kerr, Hugo Muench, Henry Kumm, John C. Bugher, Ping Yao Cheng, S. A. Anthony, Grant Taylor, Lewis Strauss, L. S. Taylor, Shields Warren, John Loutit, Robert Holmes, Keith Cannan, and James Horsfall.
File Plan note
Former Classification: IV 2A 02
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The papers of John C. Bugher were deposited with the Rockefeller Foundation Archives in 1969 by John C. Bugher and in November 1970 by Mrs. John C. Bugher.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for scholarly research, except where particular restrictions are noted (in Series 1.2).
RAC is unable to provide access to obsolete media and original digital media. In addition separated media may not yet have undergone stabilization procedures. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Head of Archival Services or RAC Head of Digital Programs for details.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
Malaria; Nuclear medicine; Pathology; Leukemia; Radiation; Legislative hearings -- United States; Yellow fever; Cancer; Japan; Civil defense; Genetics; Radiobiology; Diseases; Loutit, John F.; Warren, Shields; Taylor, L. S.; Strauss, Lewis L.; Taylor, Grant; Cheng, Ping-Yao; Kumm, Henry W. (Henry William); Muench, Hugo; Putnam, Persis; Kerr, J. Austin, 1900-; Cannan, R. Keith (Robert Keith); Holmes, Robert; U.S. Atomic Energy Commission; U.S. Atomic Energy Commission. Division of Biology and Medicine; Bugher, John C.; Loutit, John F.; Warren, Shields; Taylor, L. S.; Strauss, Lewis L.; Taylor, Grant; Cheng, Ping-Yao; Kumm, Henry W. (Henry William); Muench, Hugo; Putnam, Persis; Kerr, J. Austin, 1900-; Cannan, R. Keith (Robert Keith); Holmes, Robert; U.S. Atomic Energy Commission; U.S. Atomic Energy Commission. Division of Biology and Medicine; Bugher, John C.
- General Files, 1
  Arrangement note
  This series is divided into two subseries:
  Subseries 1 - Pre 1950
  Subseries 2 - Post 1950
  - General Files - Pre 1950, before 1950; 1
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically, mainly by subject.
    Scope and Contents note
    Subseries 1 contains material before 1950, mainly data and statistics.
    - Bone Cancer Data (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Leonard Bruce-Chwatt, 1947-1950 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Cancer Data, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Civilian Protection Group, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Collodion Membrane Data, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Collodion Membrane Data, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1945-1952 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1945-1952 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Development of Error Function, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Diary, 1941-1949 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Diphtheria, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Forests of the British Cameroons, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Geiger Counter Data, 1949-1951 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Geiger Muller Tubes, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Gordon Toxological Conference, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Ichiro Hayashi, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - International Health Division (IHD) Program, 1948-1950 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Influenza, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Influenza Manuscript, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Laboratory Notebooks, 1947-1949 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Leukemia, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Malaria - Africa, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Malaria Yellow Fever Survey - Mokewa, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      Related Archival Materials note
      Photographs.
    - Medical Planning for Disasters Civil Defense Seminar, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Michigan Association of Chiefs of Police Scientific Identification Committee Minutes, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Miscellaneous Data, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Miscellaneous Data, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Miscellaneous Data, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Miscellaneous Data, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Miscellaneous Data, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Mosquito Locality Records - Nigeria Gold Coast, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Muso Yellow Fever Immunity Survey, 1937-1947 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Muzo Yellow Fever Protection Test Survey - Analysis of 10-14, 15-19 Males Females Born in Muzo, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Muzo Yellow Fever Protection Test Survey - Census, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Muzo Yellow Fever Protection Test Survey - Census, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Muzo Yellow Fever Protection Test Survey - Data, Binomial Commutations, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Muzo Yellow Fever Protection Test Survey - Data, Binomial Commutations, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Muzo Yellow Fever Protection Test Survey - Code and Basic Table (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Muzo Yellow Fever Protection Test Survey - Females Born in Muzo, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Muzo Yellow Fever Protection Test Survey - Males Females Born in Muzo, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Muzo Yellow Fever Protection Test Survey - Males Females Born Outside Muzo, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Muzo Yellow Fever Protection Test Survey - % Positive, Males Females Born in Muzo, by Vereda, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Muzo Yellow Fever Protection Test Survey - % Positive Born in Muzo, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Muzo Yellow Fever Protection Test Survey - Statistics, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Muzo Yellow Fever Protection Test Survey - Eastern Western Endemic Veredas, Born In Outside Muzo (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Muzo Yellow Fever Protection Test Survey - 16 Eastern, 8 Western Veredas, Born In Muzo, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Muzo Yellow Fever Protection Test Survey - 16 Eastern, 8 Western Veredas, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Muzo Yellow Fever Protection Test Survey - 10-14 Age Analysis, 16 Eastern, 8 Western Veredas, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Muzo Yellow Fever Protection Test Survey - Length of Residence, 16 Eastern, 8 Western Veredas, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Muzo Yellow Fever Protection Test Survey - Second Bleeding (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Plant Protection Committee, 1950-1951 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Probability Equations, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Proposed Study on Tropical Viruses, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Public Health Schools, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Radioactive Mosquitoes, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - Radioactive Mosquitoes - Notes, 1947-1948 (Box 6, Folder 57)
    - Results of Protection Tests on Animal Sera - Panama, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 58)
    - Yellow Fever, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 59)
    - Yellow Fever - Ogbomosho, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 60)
    - Yellow Fever Research Institute, Yaba - Annual Report, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 61)
    - Yellow Fever Research Institute, Yaba - Semi-Annual Report, January-June 1946 (Box 6, Folder 62)
    - Yellow Fever Research Institute, Yaba - Bwamba Fever Protection Tests, 1947-1948 (Box 6, Folder 63)
    - Yellow Fever Research Institute, Yaba - Bwamba Fever Protection Tests, 1947-1948 (Box 6, Folder 64)
    - Yellow Fever Research Institute, Yaba - Intracerebral Protection Tests, 1944-1946 (Box 6, Folder 65)
    - Yellow Fever Research Institute, Yaba - Intracerebral Protection Tests, 1944-1946 (Box 6, Folder 66)
    - Yellow Fever Research Institute, Yaba - Intracerebral Protection Tests, 1944-1946 (Box 6, Folder 67)
    - Yellow Fever Research Institute, Yaba - Subcutaneous Intracerebral Protection Tests, 1947-1948 (Box 6, Folder 68)
    - Yellow Fever Research Institute, Yaba - Subcutaneous Intracerebral Protection Tests, 1947-1948 (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - General Files - Post 1950, 1950-1968; 2
    Arrangement
    Persistent ID Ref484; Mixed material Box 25/Folder 395 deleted becasue NOT USED
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically by person and subject.
    Subseries 2 is post 1950 material. This subseries documents a wide range of subjects from information retrieval to symposia and civil defense.
    - Aerojet General Nucleonics, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 70)
    - Lyle Alexander, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 71)
    - Russell de Alvarez, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 72)
    - American Assembly, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 73)
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 74)
    - "American City", 1957 (Box 7, Folder 75)
    - American College of Radiology, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 76)
    - American Eugenics Society, 1957-1959 (Box 7, Folder 77)
      Hereditary Counseling Symposium participant Frederick Osborne.
    - American Institute of Biological Sciences, 1952-1963 (Box 7, Folder 78)
      Biological Sciences, curriculum study, journal exchange. Charles Shilling, Arnold Grobman.
    - American Institute of Biological Sciences, 1952-1963 (Box 7, Folder 79)
    - American Institute of Biological Sciences, 1952-1963 (Box 7, Folder 80)
    - American Institute of Biological Sciences, 1952-1963 (Box 7, Folder 81)
    - American Institute of Biological Sciences, 1952-1963 (Box 7, Folder 82)
    - American Nuclear Society Fellow, 1956-1965 (Box 7, Folder 83)
    - American Nuclear Society Fellow, 1956-1965 (Box 7, Folder 84)
    - American Nuclear Society - Bylaws Rules Committee, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 85)
    - American Nuclear Society - Bylaws Rules Committee, 1959-1961 (Box 8, Folder 86)
    - American Public Health Association - Bronfman Lecture, 1961-1963 (Box 8, Folder 87)
      "Perspectives of Our Radioactive World"
    - American Public Health Association - Committee on Professional Education, 1960-1963 (Box 8, Folder 88)
      Thomas Parran.
    - American Public Health Association - Program Area Committee Radiological Health, 1959-1964 (Box 8, Folder 89)
      James Terrill.
    - American Public Health Association - Program Area Committee Radiological Health - Reports, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 90)
    - American Public Health Association - Program Area Committee Radiological Health - Reports, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 91)
    - American Public Health Association - Program Area Committee Radiological Health - Reports, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 92)
    - American Public Health Association - Task Force, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 93)
    - American Public Health Association - Task Force Reports, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 94)
    - Gaylord Anderson, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 95)
    - Jon Anderson, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 96)
    - Howard Andrews, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 97)
    - S. A. Anthony, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 98)
    - Raymond Appleyard, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 99)
    - Associated Nucleonics, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 100)
    - Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission, 1955-1957 (Box 9, Folder 101)
      National Academy of Sciences and National Research Council. Advisory Committee on Japan Program. Radiation exposure, genetics studies. Robert Holmes, Shields Warren, Thomas Parran, Keith Cannan.
    - Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission, 1955-1957 (Box 9, Folder 102)
    - Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission, 1955-1957 (Box 9, Folder 103)
    - Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission, April-July 1956 (Box 9, Folder 103A)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Restricted material.
    - Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission, 1955-1957 (Box 9, Folder 104)
    - Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission, August-December 1956 (Box 9, Folder 104A)
    - Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission, 1955-1957 (Box 9, Folder 105)
    - Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission, 1955-1957 (Box 9, Folder 106)
    - Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission, 1960-1962 (Box 10, Folder 107)
    - Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission, 1960-1962 (Box 10, Folder 108)
    - Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission, 1960-1962 (Box 10, Folder 109)
    - Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission - Reports, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 110)
    - Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission - Reports, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 111)
    - Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission - Japan Trip 1956 (Box 10, Folder 112)
    - Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission - Japan Trip 1956 (Box 10, Folder 113)
    - Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission - Japan Trip Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 114)
    - Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission - Japan Trip Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 115)
    - Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission - Japan Trip Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 116)
    - Atomic Industrial Forum, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 117)
      Atomic Energy Commission (AEC) Research & Development installations.
    - Awards, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 118)
    - Marshall C. Balfour, 1955-1960 (Box 11, Folder 119)
    - F. W. Barber, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 120)
    - C. I. Barnard, 1951 (Box 11, Folder 121)
    - Bernard M. Baruch, 1956-1957 (Box 11, Folder 122)
      Control of atomic energy.
    - Jeanne C. Bateman, 1956-1959 (Box 11, Folder 123)
      Cancer research.
    - Jeanne C. Bateman - Data (Box 11, Folder 124)
    - John Bateman, 1957-1958 (Box 11, Folder 125)
    - Leona Baumgartner, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 126)
    - Paul Beaver, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 127)
      Yellow fever article review.
    - Philip Becker, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 128)
    - Richard Behrman, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 129)
      Collaboration on projects.
    - Belem Virus Laboratory - Progress Report, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 130)
    - Albert Bellamy, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 131)
      Civil Defense.
    - G. Bernardini, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 132)
    - George Bevier, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 133)
    - Martin Bickford, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 134)
    - Barry Bingham, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 135)
    - Thorkild Bjerge, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 136)
    - Harry Blair, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 137)
    - Blakiston Division of McGraw-Hill, 1956-1957 (Box 11, Folder 138)
    - Bone Sarcoma, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 139)
    - Bone Sarcoma, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 140)
    - Victor Bond, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 141)
    - C. F. Bonilla, 1959 (Box 12, Folder 142)
    - Jorge Boshell, 1964-1965 (Box 12, Folder 143)
    - W. R. Boss, 1956 (Box 12, Folder 144)
    - Chester Bowles, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 145)
    - Norris Bradbury, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 146)
    - Brazil - Radiation Health, 1957-1959 (Box 12, Folder 147)
      Genetics, Iowa State College project. Dosimeter film. Long term effects of radiation. Shields Warren, Thomas Parran.
    - Brazil - Radiation Health, 1957-1959 (Box 12, Folder 148)
    - Brazil - Radiation Health Reports, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 149)
    - Brazil Trip, 1957-1958 (Box 12, Folder 150)
    - John Britten, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 151)
    - Brookhaven National Laboratory - Inter-American Symposium on the Peaceful Application of Nuclear Energy, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 152)
    - Brookhaven National Laboratory - Naval Reserve Nuclear Sciences Seminar, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 153)
    - Brookhaven National Laboratory - Pathology Symposium, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 154)
    - Brookhaven National Laboratory - Visiting Committee, 1957-1961 (Box 13, Folder 155)
      Medical Department, Chairman.
    - H. D. Bruner, 1959-1960 (Box 13, Folder 156)
    - John Bugher, 1942, 1951-1966 (Box 13, Folder 157)
    - John Bugher, 1942, 1951-1966 (Box 13, Folder 158)
    - John Bugher, 1942, 1951-1966 (Box 13, Folder 159)
    - John Bugher - Bibliography, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 160)
    - Charles Burnett, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 161)
    - Robert Butenhoff, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 162)
    - Adriana Buzzati - Traverso, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 163)
    - Ralph Calvert, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 164)
    - Melvin Calvin, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 165)
    - Cancer, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 166)
    - Cancer Retreat, 1955-1956 (Box 13, Folder 167)
      University of Michigan symposium participant.
      Photos removed to RAC Photograph Collection, Series 1010.
    - M. G. Candau, 1959-1962 (Box 13, Folder 168)
    - Erwin Canham, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 169)
    - Keith Cannan, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 170)
    - Simeon Cantril, 1956-1959 (Box 14, Folder 171)
    - Catholic University, Louvain, 1960 (Box 14, Folder 172)
    - Paul Caubin, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 173)
    - Silvio Ceccato, 1960 (Box 14, Folder 174)
    - Chagas Disease Congress, 1958-1960 (Box 14, Folder 175)
      Chagas disease, radiation.
    - Martin Charles, 1958-1960 (Box 14, Folder 176)
    - Charles C. Thomas, Publisher, 1958-1960 (Box 14, Folder 177)
    - Ping Yao, Cheng, 1959-1966 (Box 14, Folder 178)
      Advisory Committee for Biology and Medicine (ACBM).